WENDY HUANG

I want to build tools for humans

M melonh0327@gmail.com nttps://github.com/melonHuang

(86)18588640327



I'm a Senior Front-End Engineer with 4 years working experience. Crafting interesting and useful tools is my jam. In the recent past, I have given talks at development conferences, started several open source projects, and actively participated in the translation of technical books.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2013 - 2017 Qihoo 360 Technology Co. Lt

Senior Front-End Developer - Annual Excellent Employee of department

2016 - 2017 Shengxiang - an online presentation editor

- Led a team of four Front-End developers, enforced coding standards, kept the group engaged and passionate.
- Designed predictable, scalable architecture with Vue&Vuex (React&Redux alike Javascript libraries).
- Automated workflow for development, testing, and production environment with Gulp, Webpack, PostCSS, etc.
- Designed database tables and implemented Back-End logics and APIs using ThinkJS (a Back-End MVC Framework).
- Designed innovative features and transformed them into coordinated ART and IT deliverables.

2015 - 2016 Baomitu - an interactive mobile storytelling platform

■ Built componentized architecture by designing Nova.js (a web component framework like Polymer).

2014 - 2015 **Mobile Guard Department**

- Developed official websites, mobile-side pages for special events and cross-device webviews.
- Made quick response and decisions to several independent and concurrent requirements every day, while making effective plans and guaranteeing high quality deliverables.
- Delivered high performance and compatible cross-device web pages.
- Designed NovaUI (an open source mobile-side component gallery) to share common mobile-side components with

2013 - 2014 **CRM System**

- Wrote consistent, concise, and well documented codes to build pages full of form manipulations and charts.
- Abstracted and designed common plugins for reusability.

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

2015 - 2016 Nova.is

A production-ready Web Component Framework, only 12KB after gziped, providing an easy way to define custom element with data binding, CSS Scoping, etc.

2013 - 2016 Novalli

A mobile side component gallery with high animation performance, flexible APIs and clear documents.

2014 - 2014 AnimationGenerator

A Chrome Devtools extension which can help generate animation codes for web pages quickly.

□ SPEAKING

III PLUBLICATIONS

EDUCATION

2009 - 2013

The 2nd CSSConf of China

High Performance Animation

Other talks

How Browser Renders. Mobile-side Development, Web Component, etc

Large Scale Javascript

Translated Chapters 8 - 19 from English to Madarine

The Mobile Handbook

Translated Chapters 3 - 4 from English to

Mandarine

SKILLS

Modern Web Stack

- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, DOM scripting Performance Optimization
- o Mobile-Side development, responsive web design
- Node.js and MVC Back-End Framework
- Network knowleges including HTTP protol, TCP handshakes, etc
- Fullstack, able to design database tables, implement Back-End logics and design UI
- · Good documenting habit

Rich Experience in

- · Large-scale web applications, designing scalable architecture and workflow
- Javascript Application Framework Vue.js
- Cross-browser and cross-device development, handling compatibility issues

Tools

o npm, gulp, webpack, postCSS, babel, thinkjs, eslint, mocha.js, chai.js, etc

Sun Yat-sen University

Software Engineering BSc

- o vim, git/svn, chrome devtools, photoshop, zsh. etc
- · Vue.js, Polymer, jQuery, Zepto, etc